<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-09-15T23:47:50+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Trineurotec</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">High sucrose consumption during pregnancy induced ADHD-like behavioral phenotypes in mice offspring.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2015/12/10/highsucrose.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High sucrose consumption during pregnancy induced ADHD-like behavioral phenotypes in mice offspring." /><published>2015-12-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2015-12-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2015/12/10/highsucrose</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2015/12/10/highsucrose.html">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the average consumption of sugar in humans from all ages has remarkably increased,
exceeding the recommended limit. Pregnancy is a critical time for the global development of offsprings who are vulnerable to the deleterious effects of environmental factors. In this study, we investigated whether high sucrose consumption during pregnancy could affect the attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)-like neurobehavioral outcomes in offspring mice. Pregnant mice were randomly grouped and orally administered with either water as control (Con) or 30% wt/vol sucrose diluted in water at 6 (Suc6) or 9 (Suc9) g/kg dosage per day from gestational days 6 to 15. After the weaning period, offspring mice underwent a series of behavioral testing for locomotor activity, attention, and impulsivity. Although there is no obvious difference in gross development of offspring mice such as weight gain, high sucrose-exposed offspring mice showed a significantly increased locomotor activity. Moreover, these mice exhibited a dose-dependent decrease in attention and increase in impulsivity. In the striatum, a significantly increased dopamine transporter (DAT) mRNA expression was found in the Suc9 group along with dose-dependent decreases in the Drd1, Drd2 and Drd4 dopamine receptor subtypes. Furthermore, synaptosomal DAT protein expression was increased about twofold in the Suc9 group. Prenatal fructose exposure also induced hyperactive behavior in offspring mice suggesting the essential role of fructose in the dysregulated neurobehavioral development. These findings suggest prenatal sucrose consumption as a new risk factor for ADHD, which may need further attention and investigation in humans.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Choi CS, Kim P, Park JH, Gonzales EL, Kim KC, Cho KS, Ko MJ, Yang SM, Seung H, Han SH, Ryu JH, Cheong JH, Shin CY.</name></author><summary type="html">In recent years, the average consumption of sugar in humans from all ages has remarkably increased, exceeding the recommended limit. Pregnancy is a critical time for the global development of offsprings who are vulnerable to the deleterious effects of environmental factors. In this study, we investigated whether high sucrose consumption during pregnancy could affect the attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)-like neurobehavioral outcomes in offspring mice. Pregnant mice were randomly grouped and orally administered with either water as control (Con) or 30% wt/vol sucrose diluted in water at 6 (Suc6) or 9 (Suc9) g/kg dosage per day from gestational days 6 to 15. After the weaning period, offspring mice underwent a series of behavioral testing for locomotor activity, attention, and impulsivity. Although there is no obvious difference in gross development of offspring mice such as weight gain, high sucrose-exposed offspring mice showed a significantly increased locomotor activity. Moreover, these mice exhibited a dose-dependent decrease in attention and increase in impulsivity. In the striatum, a significantly increased dopamine transporter (DAT) mRNA expression was found in the Suc9 group along with dose-dependent decreases in the Drd1, Drd2 and Drd4 dopamine receptor subtypes. Furthermore, synaptosomal DAT protein expression was increased about twofold in the Suc9 group. Prenatal fructose exposure also induced hyperactive behavior in offspring mice suggesting the essential role of fructose in the dysregulated neurobehavioral development. These findings suggest prenatal sucrose consumption as a new risk factor for ADHD, which may need further attention and investigation in humans.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Effects of atomoxetine on hyper-locomotive activity of the prenatally valproate-exposed rat offspring.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2014/09/10/Effects-of-atomoxetine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Effects of atomoxetine on hyper-locomotive activity of the prenatally valproate-exposed rat offspring." /><published>2014-09-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2014-09-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2014/09/10/Effects%20of%20atomoxetine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2014/09/10/Effects-of-atomoxetine.html">&lt;p&gt;A substantial proportion of patients with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) display hyperactivity as a comorbid symptom. Exposure to valproic acid (VPA) during pregnancy produces ASD-like core behavioral phenotypes as well as hyperactivity in offspring both in human and experimental animals, which makes it a plausible model to study ASD-related neurobiological processes. In this study, we examined the effects of two of currently available attention defecit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) medications, methylphenidate (MPH) and atomoxetine (ATX) targeting dopamine and norepinephrine transporters (DAT and NET), respectively, on hyperactive behavior of prenatally VPA-exposed rat offspring. In the prefrontal cortex of VPA exposed rat offspring, both mRNA and protein expression of DAT was increased as compared with control. VPA function as a histone deacetylase inhibitor (HDACi) and chromatin immunoprecipitation experiments demonstrated that the acetylation of histone bound to DAT gene promoter was increased in VPA-exposed rat offspring suggesting epigenetic mechanism of DAT regulation. Similarly, the expression of NET was increased, possibly via increased histone acetylation in prefrontal cortex of VPA-exposed rat offspring. When we treated the VPA-exposed rat offspring with ATX, a NET selective inhibitor, hyperactivity was reversed to control level. In contrast, MPH that inhibits both DAT and NET, did not produce inhibitory effects against hyperactivity. The results suggest that NET abnormalities may underlie the hyperactive phenotype in VPA animal model of ASD. Profiling the pharmacological responsiveness as well as investigating underlying mechanism in multiple models of ASD and ADHD may provide more insights into the neurobiological correlates regulating the behavioral abnormalities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Choi CS, Hong M, Kim KC, Kim JW, Yang SM, Seung H, Ko MJ, Choi DH, You JS, Shin CY, Bahn GH</name></author><summary type="html">A substantial proportion of patients with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) display hyperactivity as a comorbid symptom. Exposure to valproic acid (VPA) during pregnancy produces ASD-like core behavioral phenotypes as well as hyperactivity in offspring both in human and experimental animals, which makes it a plausible model to study ASD-related neurobiological processes. In this study, we examined the effects of two of currently available attention defecit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) medications, methylphenidate (MPH) and atomoxetine (ATX) targeting dopamine and norepinephrine transporters (DAT and NET), respectively, on hyperactive behavior of prenatally VPA-exposed rat offspring. In the prefrontal cortex of VPA exposed rat offspring, both mRNA and protein expression of DAT was increased as compared with control. VPA function as a histone deacetylase inhibitor (HDACi) and chromatin immunoprecipitation experiments demonstrated that the acetylation of histone bound to DAT gene promoter was increased in VPA-exposed rat offspring suggesting epigenetic mechanism of DAT regulation. Similarly, the expression of NET was increased, possibly via increased histone acetylation in prefrontal cortex of VPA-exposed rat offspring. When we treated the VPA-exposed rat offspring with ATX, a NET selective inhibitor, hyperactivity was reversed to control level. In contrast, MPH that inhibits both DAT and NET, did not produce inhibitory effects against hyperactivity. The results suggest that NET abnormalities may underlie the hyperactive phenotype in VPA animal model of ASD. Profiling the pharmacological responsiveness as well as investigating underlying mechanism in multiple models of ASD and ADHD may provide more insights into the neurobiological correlates regulating the behavioral abnormalities.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chronic exposure to ethanol of male mice before mating produces attention deficit hyperactivity disorder-like phenotype along with epigenetic dysregulation of dopamine transporter expression in mouse offspring.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2014/05/10/chronic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chronic exposure to ethanol of male mice before mating produces attention deficit hyperactivity disorder-like phenotype along with epigenetic dysregulation of dopamine transporter expression in mouse offspring." /><published>2014-05-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2014-05-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2014/05/10/chronic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2014/05/10/chronic.html">&lt;p&gt;Preconception exposure to EtOH through the paternal route may affect neurobehavioral and developmental features of offspring. This study investigates the effects of paternal exposure to EtOH before conception on the hyperactivity, inattention, and impulsivity behavior of male offspring in mice. Sire mice were treated with EtOH in a concentration range approximating human binge drinking (0-4 g/kg/day EtOH) for 7 weeks and mated with untreated females mice to produce offspring. EtOH exposure to sire mice induced attention deficit hyperactivitydisorder (ADHD)-like hyperactive, inattentive, and impulsive behaviors in offspring. As a mechanistic link, both protein and mRNA expression of dopamine transporter (DAT), a key determinant of ADHD-like phenotypes in experimental animals and humans, were significantly decreased by paternal EtOH exposure in cerebral cortex and striatum of offspring mice along with increased methylation of a CpG region of the DAT gene promoter. The increase in methylation of DAT gene promoter was also observed in the sperm of sire mice, suggesting germline changes in the epigenetic methylation signature of DAT gene by EtOH exposure. In addition, the expression of two key regulators of methylation-dependent epigenetic regulation of functional gene expression, namely, MeCP2 and DNMT1, was markedly decreased in offspring cortex and striatum sired by EtOH-exposed mice. These results suggest that preconceptional exposure to EtOH through the paternal route induces behavioral changes in offspring, possibly via epigenetic changes in gene expression, which is essential for the regulation of ADHD-like behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kim P, Choi CS, Park JH, Joo SH, Kim SY, Ko HM, Kim KC, Jeon SJ, Park SH, Han SH, Ryu JH, Cheong JH, Han JY, Ko KN, Shin CY</name></author><summary type="html">Preconception exposure to EtOH through the paternal route may affect neurobehavioral and developmental features of offspring. This study investigates the effects of paternal exposure to EtOH before conception on the hyperactivity, inattention, and impulsivity behavior of male offspring in mice. Sire mice were treated with EtOH in a concentration range approximating human binge drinking (0-4 g/kg/day EtOH) for 7 weeks and mated with untreated females mice to produce offspring. EtOH exposure to sire mice induced attention deficit hyperactivitydisorder (ADHD)-like hyperactive, inattentive, and impulsive behaviors in offspring. As a mechanistic link, both protein and mRNA expression of dopamine transporter (DAT), a key determinant of ADHD-like phenotypes in experimental animals and humans, were significantly decreased by paternal EtOH exposure in cerebral cortex and striatum of offspring mice along with increased methylation of a CpG region of the DAT gene promoter. The increase in methylation of DAT gene promoter was also observed in the sperm of sire mice, suggesting germline changes in the epigenetic methylation signature of DAT gene by EtOH exposure. In addition, the expression of two key regulators of methylation-dependent epigenetic regulation of functional gene expression, namely, MeCP2 and DNMT1, was markedly decreased in offspring cortex and striatum sired by EtOH-exposed mice. These results suggest that preconceptional exposure to EtOH through the paternal route induces behavioral changes in offspring, possibly via epigenetic changes in gene expression, which is essential for the regulation of ADHD-like behaviors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prefrontal cortical and striatal transcriptional responses to the reinforcing effect of repeated methylphenidate treatment in the spontaneously hypertensive rat, animal model of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD).</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2014/05/06/Prefrontal-cortical-and-striatal-transcriptional.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prefrontal cortical and striatal transcriptional responses to the reinforcing effect of repeated methylphenidate treatment in the spontaneously hypertensive rat, animal model of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)." /><published>2014-05-06T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2014-05-06T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2014/05/06/Prefrontal%20cortical%20and%20striatal%20transcriptional</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2014/05/06/Prefrontal-cortical-and-striatal-transcriptional.html">&lt;p&gt;BACKGROUND:
Methylphenidate is the most commonly used stimulant drug for the treatment of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder(ADHD). Research has found that methylphenidate is a “reinforcer” and that individuals with ADHD also abuse this medication. Nevertheless, the molecular consequences of long-term recreational methylphenidate use or abuse in individuals with ADHD are not yet fully known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;METHODS:
Spontaneously hypertensive rats (SHR), the most validated and widely used ADHD animal model, were pretreated with methylphenidate (5 mg/kg, i.p.) during their adolescence (post-natal day [PND] 42-48) and tested for subsequent methylphenidate-induced conditioned place preference (CPP) and self-administration. Thereafter, the differentially expressed genes in the prefrontal cortex (PFC) and striatum of representative methylphenidate-treated SHRs, which showed CPP to and self-administration of methylphenidate, were analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RESULTS:
Genome-wide transcriptome profiling analyses revealed 30 differentially expressed genes in the PFC, which include transcripts involved in apoptosis (e.g. S100a9, Angptl4, Nfkbia), transcription (Cebpb, Per3), and neuronal plasticity (Homer1, Jam2, Asap1). In contrast, 306 genes were differentially expressed in the striatum and among them, 252 were downregulated. The main functional categories overrepresented among the downregulated genes include those involved in cell adhesion (e.g. Pcdh10, Ctbbd1, Itgb6), positive regulation of apoptosis (Perp, Taf1, Api5), (Notch3, Nsbp1, Sik1), mitochondrion organization (Prps18c, Letm1, Uqcrc2), and ubiquitin-mediated proteolysis (Nedd4, Usp27x, Ube2d2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CONCLUSION:
Together, these changes indicate methylphenidate-induced neurotoxicity, altered synaptic and neuronal plasticity, energy metabolism and ubiquitin-dependent protein degradation in the brains of methylphenidate-treated SHRs, which showed methylphenidate CPP and self-administration. In addition, these findings may also reflect cognitive impairment associated with chronic methylphenidate use as demonstrated in preclinical studies. Future studies are warranted to determine the clinical significance of the present findings with regard to long-term recreational methylphenidate use or abuse in individuals with ADHD.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dela Peña I, Kim HJ, Sohn A, Kim BN, Han DH, Ryu JH, Shin CY, Noh M, Cheong JH</name></author><summary type="html">BACKGROUND: Methylphenidate is the most commonly used stimulant drug for the treatment of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder(ADHD). Research has found that methylphenidate is a “reinforcer” and that individuals with ADHD also abuse this medication. Nevertheless, the molecular consequences of long-term recreational methylphenidate use or abuse in individuals with ADHD are not yet fully known.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5,7-Dihydroxy-6-methoxy-4’-phenoxyflavone, a derivative of oroxylin A improves attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)-like behaviors in spontaneously hypertensive rats</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2013/09/05/5,7-Dihydroxy-6-methoxy-4'-phenoxyflavone,.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5,7-Dihydroxy-6-methoxy-4'-phenoxyflavone, a derivative of oroxylin A improves attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)-like behaviors in spontaneously hypertensive rats" /><published>2013-09-05T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2013-09-05T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2013/09/05/5,7-Dihydroxy-6-methoxy-4'-phenoxyflavone,</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2013/09/05/5,7-Dihydroxy-6-methoxy-4'-phenoxyflavone,.html">&lt;p&gt;Oroxylin A, a major flavonoid in Scutellaria baicalensis, has been shown to alleviate attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)-like behaviors in the spontaneously hypertensive rat (SHR) model of ADHD. As part of our continuing effort to discover effective ADHD drug candidates, we synthesized a number of oroxylin A derivatives and characterized their biological activities. Among all oroxylin A analogs, compound 7-7 (5,7-dihydroxy-6-methoxy-4’-phenoxyflavone) showed the most remarkable inhibition of dopamine reuptake alike methylphenidate, a dopamine transporter (DAT) blocker and typical drug for ADHD, and oroxylin A. It did not influence norepinephrine reuptake unlike atomoxetine, a selective norepinephrine inhibitor. Moreover, compound 7-7 reduced hyperactivity, sustained inattention and impulsivity in the SHR as measured by the open field, Y-maze and electro-foot shock aversive water drinking tests, respectively. Most drugs that enhance brain dopamine levels (e.g. DAT blockers like cocaine and methylphenidate) produce behavioral effects like those of stimulants causing them to be abused. However, the repeated treatment of compound 7-7 failed to elicit locomotor sensitization in rats, and neither produced conditioned place preference response nor maintained self-administration behavior. Altogether, the present study suggests the promising therapeutic value of compound 7-7 as an ADHD drug. Furthermore, compound 7-7 may be considered as an alternative therapy to psychostimulant ADHD treatments (e.g. amphetamine and methylphenidate) for which use has been deemed controversial due to their abuse liability.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dela Peña IC, Young Yoon S, Kim Y, Park H, Man Kim K, Hoon Ryu J, Young Shin C, Hoon Cheong J</name></author><summary type="html">Oroxylin A, a major flavonoid in Scutellaria baicalensis, has been shown to alleviate attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)-like behaviors in the spontaneously hypertensive rat (SHR) model of ADHD. As part of our continuing effort to discover effective ADHD drug candidates, we synthesized a number of oroxylin A derivatives and characterized their biological activities. Among all oroxylin A analogs, compound 7-7 (5,7-dihydroxy-6-methoxy-4’-phenoxyflavone) showed the most remarkable inhibition of dopamine reuptake alike methylphenidate, a dopamine transporter (DAT) blocker and typical drug for ADHD, and oroxylin A. It did not influence norepinephrine reuptake unlike atomoxetine, a selective norepinephrine inhibitor. Moreover, compound 7-7 reduced hyperactivity, sustained inattention and impulsivity in the SHR as measured by the open field, Y-maze and electro-foot shock aversive water drinking tests, respectively. Most drugs that enhance brain dopamine levels (e.g. DAT blockers like cocaine and methylphenidate) produce behavioral effects like those of stimulants causing them to be abused. However, the repeated treatment of compound 7-7 failed to elicit locomotor sensitization in rats, and neither produced conditioned place preference response nor maintained self-administration behavior. Altogether, the present study suggests the promising therapeutic value of compound 7-7 as an ADHD drug. Furthermore, compound 7-7 may be considered as an alternative therapy to psychostimulant ADHD treatments (e.g. amphetamine and methylphenidate) for which use has been deemed controversial due to their abuse liability.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Effects of ethanol exposure during early pregnancy in hyperactive, inattentive and impulsive behaviors and MeCP2 expression in rodent offspring</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2013/03/10/ethanol.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Effects of ethanol exposure during early pregnancy in hyperactive, inattentive and impulsive behaviors and MeCP2 expression in rodent offspring" /><published>2013-03-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2013-03-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2013/03/10/ethanol</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2013/03/10/ethanol.html">&lt;p&gt;Prenatal exposure to alcohol has consistently been associated with adverse effects on neurodevelopment, which is collectively called fetal alcohol spectrum disorder (FASD). Increasing evidence suggest that prenatal exposure to alcohol increases the risk of developing attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder-like behavior in human. In this study, we investigated the behavioral effects of prenatal exposure to EtOH in offspring mice and rats focusing on hyperactivity and impulsivity. We also examined changes in dopamine transporter and MeCP2 expression, which may underlie as a key neurobiological and epigenetic determinant in FASD and hyperactive, inattentive and impulsive behaviors. Mouse or rat offspring born from dam exposed to alcohol during pregnancy (EtOH group) showed hyper locomotive activity, attention deficit and impulsivity. EtOH group also showed increased dopamine transporter and norepinephrine transporter level compared to control group in the prefrontal cortex and striatum. Prenatal exposure to EtOH also significantly decreased the expression of MeCP2 in both prefrontal cortex and striatum. These results suggest that prenatal exposure to EtOH induces hyperactive, inattentive and impulsive behaviors in rodent offspring that might be related to global epigenetic changes as well as aberration in catecholamine neurotransmitter transporter system.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kim P, Park JH, Choi CS, Choi I, Joo SH, Kim MK, Kim SY, Kim KC, Park SH, Kwon KJ, Lee J, Han SH, Ryu JH, Cheong JH, Han JY, Ko KN, Shin CY</name></author><summary type="html">Prenatal exposure to alcohol has consistently been associated with adverse effects on neurodevelopment, which is collectively called fetal alcohol spectrum disorder (FASD). Increasing evidence suggest that prenatal exposure to alcohol increases the risk of developing attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder-like behavior in human. In this study, we investigated the behavioral effects of prenatal exposure to EtOH in offspring mice and rats focusing on hyperactivity and impulsivity. We also examined changes in dopamine transporter and MeCP2 expression, which may underlie as a key neurobiological and epigenetic determinant in FASD and hyperactive, inattentive and impulsive behaviors. Mouse or rat offspring born from dam exposed to alcohol during pregnancy (EtOH group) showed hyper locomotive activity, attention deficit and impulsivity. EtOH group also showed increased dopamine transporter and norepinephrine transporter level compared to control group in the prefrontal cortex and striatum. Prenatal exposure to EtOH also significantly decreased the expression of MeCP2 in both prefrontal cortex and striatum. These results suggest that prenatal exposure to EtOH induces hyperactive, inattentive and impulsive behaviors in rodent offspring that might be related to global epigenetic changes as well as aberration in catecholamine neurotransmitter transporter system.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oroxylin A improves attention deficit hyperactivity disorder-like behaviors in the spontaneously hypertensive rat and inhibits reuptake of dopamine in vitro</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2013/01/10/Oroxylin-A-improves-attention.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oroxylin A improves attention deficit hyperactivity disorder-like behaviors in the spontaneously hypertensive rat and inhibits reuptake of dopamine in vitro" /><published>2013-01-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2013-01-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2013/01/10/Oroxylin%20A%20improves%20attention</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2013/01/10/Oroxylin-A-improves-attention.html">&lt;p&gt;In previous studies we have demonstrated that the γ-aminobutryic acid-A (GABA-A) receptor antagonist oroxylin A has an awakening effect and it also represses ADHD-like behaviors (hyperactivity, impulsivity and inattention) in the spontaneously hypertensive rat (SHR) model of attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder(ADHD). We hypothesized that the effects of oroxylin A were exerted via the GABA-A receptor given the important role of the GABAergic system in ADHD. However, it is possible that aside from the GABAergic system, oroxylin A may influence other systems especially those implicated in ADHD (e.g. DAergic, etc.). To test this hypothesis, we evaluated the effects of GABA agonist, or dopamine (DA) antagonist in oroxylin A-induced alleviation of ADHD-like behaviors in SHR. SHR showed inattention and impulsivity as measured by the Y-maze and the electro-foot shock aversive water drinking tests, respectively. Oroxylin A significantly improved these behaviors, furthermore, its effect on SHR impulsivity was attenuated by haloperidol, a DA antagonist, but not by baicalein, an agonist of the GABA-A receptor. In vitro studies showed that oroxylin A inhibited DA uptake similar to methylphenidate, a dopamine transporter blocker, but did not influence norepinephrine uptake unlike atomoxetine, a selective NE reuptake inhibitor. Collectively, the present findings suggest that oroxylin A improves ADHD-like behaviors in SHR via enhancement of DA neurotransmission and not modulation of GABA pathway as previously reported. Importantly, the present study indicates the potential therapeutic value of oroxylin A in the treatment of ADHD.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Yoon SY, dela Peña I, Kim SM, Woo TS, Shin CY, Son KH, Park H, Lee YS, Ryu JH, Jin M, Kim KM, Cheong JH</name></author><summary type="html">In previous studies we have demonstrated that the γ-aminobutryic acid-A (GABA-A) receptor antagonist oroxylin A has an awakening effect and it also represses ADHD-like behaviors (hyperactivity, impulsivity and inattention) in the spontaneously hypertensive rat (SHR) model of attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder(ADHD). We hypothesized that the effects of oroxylin A were exerted via the GABA-A receptor given the important role of the GABAergic system in ADHD. However, it is possible that aside from the GABAergic system, oroxylin A may influence other systems especially those implicated in ADHD (e.g. DAergic, etc.). To test this hypothesis, we evaluated the effects of GABA agonist, or dopamine (DA) antagonist in oroxylin A-induced alleviation of ADHD-like behaviors in SHR. SHR showed inattention and impulsivity as measured by the Y-maze and the electro-foot shock aversive water drinking tests, respectively. Oroxylin A significantly improved these behaviors, furthermore, its effect on SHR impulsivity was attenuated by haloperidol, a DA antagonist, but not by baicalein, an agonist of the GABA-A receptor. In vitro studies showed that oroxylin A inhibited DA uptake similar to methylphenidate, a dopamine transporter blocker, but did not influence norepinephrine uptake unlike atomoxetine, a selective NE reuptake inhibitor. Collectively, the present findings suggest that oroxylin A improves ADHD-like behaviors in SHR via enhancement of DA neurotransmission and not modulation of GABA pathway as previously reported. Importantly, the present study indicates the potential therapeutic value of oroxylin A in the treatment of ADHD.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Effects of Preconceptional Ethanol Consumption on ADHD-Like Symptoms in Sprague-Dawley Rat Offsprings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2012/03/10/Effects-of-Preconceptional-Ethanol.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Effects of Preconceptional Ethanol Consumption on ADHD-Like Symptoms in Sprague-Dawley Rat Offsprings" /><published>2012-03-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2012-03-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2012/03/10/Effects%20of%20Preconceptional%20Ethanol</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2012/03/10/Effects-of-Preconceptional-Ethanol.html">&lt;p&gt;Ethanol exposure during gestational period is related to growth retardation, morphological abnormality, and even in neurological abnormalities including attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)-like behaviors on offspring. However, relatively little is known about the effects of maternal ethanol consumption prior to conception on their offspring. In this study, we investi-gated whether maternal ethanol administration during preconceptional phase produces ADHD-like behaviors in the rat offspring. Sprague-Dawley (SD) female rats were administrated ethanol via intragastric intubation with dosing regimen of 6 g/kg daily for 10 consecutive days and treated female rats then mated with non-treated male SD rats after 8 weeks. Another group subjected to the same procedure as those conducted on ethanol treated group except the saline administration instead of ethanol. Offspring was tested for their ADHD-like behaviors using open field test, Y maze test and impulsivity test that is performed in the aversive electronic foot shock paradigm. Offspring of preconceptional ethanol treated (EtOH) group showed hyperlocomotive activity, attention deficit and impulsivity. And reduction of striatal dopamine transporter (DAT) level was observed by Western blot in the EtOH group, compared to control (Con) group, while the immunohistochemical analysis exhibited increased expression of norepinephrine transporter (NET) in the frontal cortex. These results suggest that maternal ethanol consumption in the preconceptional phase induces ADHD-like behaviors in offspring that might be related to the abnormal expression of DAT and NET in rat.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Choi I, Kim P, Joo SH, Kim MK, Park JH, Kim HJ, Ryu JH, Cheong JH, Shin CY</name></author><summary type="html">Ethanol exposure during gestational period is related to growth retardation, morphological abnormality, and even in neurological abnormalities including attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)-like behaviors on offspring. However, relatively little is known about the effects of maternal ethanol consumption prior to conception on their offspring. In this study, we investi-gated whether maternal ethanol administration during preconceptional phase produces ADHD-like behaviors in the rat offspring. Sprague-Dawley (SD) female rats were administrated ethanol via intragastric intubation with dosing regimen of 6 g/kg daily for 10 consecutive days and treated female rats then mated with non-treated male SD rats after 8 weeks. Another group subjected to the same procedure as those conducted on ethanol treated group except the saline administration instead of ethanol. Offspring was tested for their ADHD-like behaviors using open field test, Y maze test and impulsivity test that is performed in the aversive electronic foot shock paradigm. Offspring of preconceptional ethanol treated (EtOH) group showed hyperlocomotive activity, attention deficit and impulsivity. And reduction of striatal dopamine transporter (DAT) level was observed by Western blot in the EtOH group, compared to control (Con) group, while the immunohistochemical analysis exhibited increased expression of norepinephrine transporter (NET) in the frontal cortex. These results suggest that maternal ethanol consumption in the preconceptional phase induces ADHD-like behaviors in offspring that might be related to the abnormal expression of DAT and NET in rat.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A simple behavioral paradigm to measure impulsive behavior in an animal model of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) of the spontaneously hypertensive rats</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2012/01/10/A-simple-behavioral-paradigm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A simple behavioral paradigm to measure impulsive behavior in an animal model of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) of the spontaneously hypertensive rats" /><published>2012-01-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2012-01-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2012/01/10/A%20simple%20behavioral%20paradigm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2012/01/10/A-simple-behavioral-paradigm.html">&lt;p&gt;Impulsiveness is an important component of many psychiatric disorders including Attention-deficit/hyperactivitydisorder (ADHD). Although the neurobiological basis of ADHD is unresolved, behavioral tests in animal models have become indispensable tools for improving our understanding of this disorder. In the punishment/extinction paradigm, impulsivity is shown by subjects that persevere with responding despite punishment or unrewarded responses. Exploiting this principle, we developed a new behavioral test that would evaluate impulsivity in the most validated animal model of ADHD of the Spontaneously Hypertensive rat (SHR) as compared with the normotensive “control” strain, the Wistar Kyoto rat (WKY). In this paradigm we call the Electro-Foot Shock aversive water Drinking test (EFSDT), water-deprived rats should pass over an electrified quadrant of the EFSDT apparatus to drink water. We reasoned that impulsive animals show increased frequency to drink water even with the presentation of an aversive consequence (electro-shock). Through this assay, we showed that the SHR was more impulsive than the WKY as it demonstrated more “drinking attempts” and drinking frequency. Methylphenidate, the most widely used ADHD medication, significantly reduced drinking frequency of both SHR and WKY in the EFSDT. Thus, the present assay may be considered as another behavioral tool to measure impulsivity in animal disease models, especially in the context of ADHD.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kim P, Choi I, Pena IC, Kim HJ, Kwon KJ, Park JH, Han SH, Ryu JH, Cheong JH, Shin CY</name></author><summary type="html">Impulsiveness is an important component of many psychiatric disorders including Attention-deficit/hyperactivitydisorder (ADHD). Although the neurobiological basis of ADHD is unresolved, behavioral tests in animal models have become indispensable tools for improving our understanding of this disorder. In the punishment/extinction paradigm, impulsivity is shown by subjects that persevere with responding despite punishment or unrewarded responses. Exploiting this principle, we developed a new behavioral test that would evaluate impulsivity in the most validated animal model of ADHD of the Spontaneously Hypertensive rat (SHR) as compared with the normotensive “control” strain, the Wistar Kyoto rat (WKY). In this paradigm we call the Electro-Foot Shock aversive water Drinking test (EFSDT), water-deprived rats should pass over an electrified quadrant of the EFSDT apparatus to drink water. We reasoned that impulsive animals show increased frequency to drink water even with the presentation of an aversive consequence (electro-shock). Through this assay, we showed that the SHR was more impulsive than the WKY as it demonstrated more “drinking attempts” and drinking frequency. Methylphenidate, the most widely used ADHD medication, significantly reduced drinking frequency of both SHR and WKY in the EFSDT. Thus, the present assay may be considered as another behavioral tool to measure impulsivity in animal disease models, especially in the context of ADHD.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conditioned place preference studies with atomoxetine in an animal model of ADHD effects of previous atomoxetine treatment</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2011/09/30/Conditioned-place-preference-studies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conditioned place preference studies with atomoxetine in an animal model of ADHD effects of previous atomoxetine treatment" /><published>2011-09-30T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2011-09-30T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2011/09/30/Conditioned%20place%20preference%20studies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2011/09/30/Conditioned-place-preference-studies.html">&lt;p&gt;To investigate the putative rewarding effects of atomoxetine, a non-stimulant medication for Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), we conducted conditioned place preference (CPP) tests in an animal model of ADHD, the spontaneously hypertensive rat (SHR). The effects of drug pre-exposure were also evaluated, thus, parallel experiments were done in rats which have undergone 14 days of atomoxetine treatment. The responses of SHR were compared with the rat strain representing the “normal” heterogeneous population, the Wistar rats. Neither rat strain showed significant CPP to atomoxetine. However, previous atomoxetine treatment produced place preference responses in rats, more profoundly in Wistar rats conditioned with the low and moderate atomoxetine doses. In conclusion, acute exposure to atomoxetine does not have any rewarding effect, however, drug pretreatment produces responses characteristic of reward or psychological dependence, more specifically in the “normal” vs. the ADHD animal model. The present findings call for more studies with atomoxetine, especially those that investigate the effects of long-term or chronic drug treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dela Peña IC, Ahn HS, Ryu JH, Shin CY, Park IH, Cheong JH</name></author><summary type="html">To investigate the putative rewarding effects of atomoxetine, a non-stimulant medication for Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), we conducted conditioned place preference (CPP) tests in an animal model of ADHD, the spontaneously hypertensive rat (SHR). The effects of drug pre-exposure were also evaluated, thus, parallel experiments were done in rats which have undergone 14 days of atomoxetine treatment. The responses of SHR were compared with the rat strain representing the “normal” heterogeneous population, the Wistar rats. Neither rat strain showed significant CPP to atomoxetine. However, previous atomoxetine treatment produced place preference responses in rats, more profoundly in Wistar rats conditioned with the low and moderate atomoxetine doses. In conclusion, acute exposure to atomoxetine does not have any rewarding effect, however, drug pretreatment produces responses characteristic of reward or psychological dependence, more specifically in the “normal” vs. the ADHD animal model. The present findings call for more studies with atomoxetine, especially those that investigate the effects of long-term or chronic drug treatment.</summary></entry></feed>