<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-09-18T12:19:19+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Trineurotec</title><subtitle>No.1 drug development company for ADHD and other neurodevelopment disorders.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Sex Differences in Autism-Like Behavioral Phenotypes and Postsynaptic Receptors Expression in the Prefrontal Cortex of TERT Transgenic Mice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2017/07/01/Sex-Differences-in-Autism-Like-Behavioral.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sex Differences in Autism-Like Behavioral Phenotypes and Postsynaptic Receptors Expression in the Prefrontal Cortex of TERT Transgenic Mice" /><published>2017-07-01T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2017-07-01T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2017/07/01/Sex%20Differences%20in%20Autism-Like%20Behavioral</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2017/07/01/Sex-Differences-in-Autism-Like-Behavioral.html">&lt;p&gt;Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) remains unexplained and untreated despite the high attention of research in recent years. Aside from its various characteristics is the baffling male preponderance over the female population. Using a validated animal model of ASD which is the telomerase reverse transcriptase overexpressing mice (TERT-tg), we conducted ASD-related behavioral assessments and protein expression experiments to mark the difference between male and females of this animal model. After statistically analyzing the results, we found significant effects of TERT overexpression in sociability, social novelty preference, anxiety, nest building, and electroseizure threshold in the males but not their female littermates. Along these differences are the male-specific increased expressions of postsynaptic proteins which are the NMDA and AMPA receptors in the prefrontal cortex. The vGluT1 presynaptic proteins, but not GAD, were upregulated in both sexes of TERT-tg mice, although it is more significantly pronounced in the male group. Here, we confirmed that the behavioral effect of TERT overexpression in mice was male-specific, suggesting that the aberration of this gene and its downstream pathways preferentially affect the functional development of the male brain, consistent with the male preponderance in ASD.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kim KC, Cho KS, Yang SM, Gonzales EL, Valencia S, Eun PH, Choi CS, Mabunga DF, Kim JW, Noh JK, Kim HJ, Jeon SJ, Han SH, Bahn GH, Shin CY</name></author><summary type="html">Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) remains unexplained and untreated despite the high attention of research in recent years. Aside from its various characteristics is the baffling male preponderance over the female population. Using a validated animal model of ASD which is the telomerase reverse transcriptase overexpressing mice (TERT-tg), we conducted ASD-related behavioral assessments and protein expression experiments to mark the difference between male and females of this animal model. After statistically analyzing the results, we found significant effects of TERT overexpression in sociability, social novelty preference, anxiety, nest building, and electroseizure threshold in the males but not their female littermates. Along these differences are the male-specific increased expressions of postsynaptic proteins which are the NMDA and AMPA receptors in the prefrontal cortex. The vGluT1 presynaptic proteins, but not GAD, were upregulated in both sexes of TERT-tg mice, although it is more significantly pronounced in the male group. Here, we confirmed that the behavioral effect of TERT overexpression in mice was male-specific, suggesting that the aberration of this gene and its downstream pathways preferentially affect the functional development of the male brain, consistent with the male preponderance in ASD.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The transgenerational inheritance of autism-like phenotypes in mice exposed to valproic acid during pregnancy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2016/11/07/The-transgenerational-inheritance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The transgenerational inheritance of autism-like phenotypes in mice exposed to valproic acid during pregnancy" /><published>2016-11-07T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2016-11-07T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2016/11/07/The%20transgenerational%20inheritance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2016/11/07/The-transgenerational-inheritance.html">&lt;p&gt;Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is a heterogeneously pervasive developmental disorder in which various genetic and environmental factors are believed to underlie its development. Recently, epigenetics has been suggested as a novel concept for ASD aetiology with a proposition that epigenetic marks can be transgenerationally inherited. Based on this assumption of epigenetics, we investigated the transgenerational inheritance of ASD-like behaviours and their related synaptic changes in the VPA animal model of ASD. The first generation (F1) VPA-exposed offspring exhibited autistic-like impaired sociability and increased marble burying. They also showed increased seizure susceptibility, hyperactivity and decreased anxiety. We mated the VPA-exposed F1 male offspring with naïve females to produce the second generation (F2), and then similarly mated the F2 to deliver the third generation (F3). Remarkably, the autism-like behavioural phenotypes found in F1 persisted to the F2 and F3. Additionally, the frontal cortices of F1 and F3 showed some imbalanced expressions of excitatory/inhibitory synaptic markers, suggesting a transgenerational epigenetic inheritance. These results open the idea that E/I imbalance and ASD-like behavioural changes induced by environmental insults in mice can be epigenetically transmitted, at least, to the third generation. This study could help explain the unprecedented increase in ASD prevalence.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Choi CS, Gonzales EL, Kim KC, Yang SM, Kim JW, Mabunga DF, Cheong JH, Han SH, Bahn GH, Shin CY</name></author><summary type="html">Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is a heterogeneously pervasive developmental disorder in which various genetic and environmental factors are believed to underlie its development. Recently, epigenetics has been suggested as a novel concept for ASD aetiology with a proposition that epigenetic marks can be transgenerationally inherited. Based on this assumption of epigenetics, we investigated the transgenerational inheritance of ASD-like behaviours and their related synaptic changes in the VPA animal model of ASD. The first generation (F1) VPA-exposed offspring exhibited autistic-like impaired sociability and increased marble burying. They also showed increased seizure susceptibility, hyperactivity and decreased anxiety. We mated the VPA-exposed F1 male offspring with naïve females to produce the second generation (F2), and then similarly mated the F2 to deliver the third generation (F3). Remarkably, the autism-like behavioural phenotypes found in F1 persisted to the F2 and F3. Additionally, the frontal cortices of F1 and F3 showed some imbalanced expressions of excitatory/inhibitory synaptic markers, suggesting a transgenerational epigenetic inheritance. These results open the idea that E/I imbalance and ASD-like behavioural changes induced by environmental insults in mice can be epigenetically transmitted, at least, to the third generation. This study could help explain the unprecedented increase in ASD prevalence.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Supplementation of Korean Red Ginseng improves behavior deviations in animal models of autism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2016/02/01/Supplementation-of-Korean-Red-Ginseng.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Supplementation of Korean Red Ginseng improves behavior deviations in animal models of autism" /><published>2016-02-01T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2016-02-01T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2016/02/01/Supplementation%20of%20Korean%20Red%20Ginseng</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2016/02/01/Supplementation-of-Korean-Red-Ginseng.html">&lt;p&gt;BACKGROUND:
Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is heterogeneous neurodevelopmental disorders that primarily display social and communication impairments and restricted/repetitive behaviors. ASD prevalence has increased in recent years, yet very limited therapeutic targets and treatments are available to counteract the incapacitating disorder. Korean Red Ginseng (KRG) is a popular herbal plant in South Korea known for its wide range of therapeutic effects and nutritional benefits and has recently been gaining great scientific attention, particularly for its positive effects in the central nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OBJECTIVES:
Thus, in this study, we investigated the therapeutic potential of KRG in alleviating the neurobehavioral deficits found in the valproic acid (VPA)-exposed mice models of ASD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DESIGN:
Starting at 21 days old (P21), VPA-exposed mice were given daily oral administrations of KRG solution (100 or 200 mg/kg) until the termination of all experiments. From P28, mice behaviors were assessed in terms of social interaction capacity (P28-29), locomotor activity (P30), repetitive behaviors (P32), short-term spatial working memory (P34), motor coordination (P36), and seizure susceptibility (P38).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RESULTS:
VPA-exposed mice showed sociability and social novelty preference deficits, hyperactivity, increased repetitive behavior, impaired spatial working memory, slightly affected motor coordination, and high seizure susceptibility. Remarkably, long-term KRG treatment in both dosages normalized all the ASD-related behaviors in VPA-exposed mice, except motor coordination ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CONCLUSION:
As a food and herbal supplement with various known benefits, KRG demonstrated its therapeutic potential in rescuing abnormal behaviors related to autism caused by prenatal environmental exposure to VPA.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gonzales EL, Jang JH, Mabunga DF, Kim JW, Ko MJ, Cho KS, Bahn GH, Hong M, Ryu JH, Kim HJ, Cheong JH, Shin CY</name></author><summary type="html">BACKGROUND: Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is heterogeneous neurodevelopmental disorders that primarily display social and communication impairments and restricted/repetitive behaviors. ASD prevalence has increased in recent years, yet very limited therapeutic targets and treatments are available to counteract the incapacitating disorder. Korean Red Ginseng (KRG) is a popular herbal plant in South Korea known for its wide range of therapeutic effects and nutritional benefits and has recently been gaining great scientific attention, particularly for its positive effects in the central nervous system.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MeCP2 Modulates Sex Differences in the Postsynaptic Development of the Valproate Animal Model of Autism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2016/01/10/MeCP2-Modulates-Sex-Differences-in-the-Postsynaptic-Development.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MeCP2 Modulates Sex Differences in the Postsynaptic Development of the Valproate Animal Model of Autism" /><published>2016-01-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2016-01-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2016/01/10/MeCP2%20Modulates%20Sex%20Differences%20in%20the%20Postsynaptic%20Development</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2016/01/10/MeCP2-Modulates-Sex-Differences-in-the-Postsynaptic-Development.html">&lt;p&gt;Males are predominantly affected by autism spectrum disorders (ASD) with a prevalence ratio of 5:1. However, the underlying pathological mechanisms governing the male preponderance of ASD remain unclear. Recent studies suggested that epigenetic aberrations may cause synaptic dysfunctions, which might be related to the pathophysiology of ASD. In this study, we used rat offspring prenatally exposed to valproic acid (VPA) as an animal model of ASD. We found male-selective abnormalities in the kinetic profile of the excitatory glutamatergic synaptic protein expressions linked to N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor (NMDAR), alpha-amino-3-hydroxy-5-methyl-4-isoxazolepropionic acid receptor (AMPAR) and metabotropic glutamate receptor 5 (mGluR5) pathways in the prefrontal cortex of the VPA-exposed offspring at postnatal weeks 1, 2, and 4. Furthermore, VPA exposure showed a male-specific attenuation of the methyl-CpG-binding protein 2 (MeCP2) expressions both in the prefrontal cortex of offspring and in the gender-isolated neural progenitor cells (NPCs). In the gender-isolated NPCs culture, higher concentration of VPA induced an increased glutamatergic synaptic development along with decreased MeCP2 expression in both genders suggesting the role of MeCP2 in the modulation of synaptic development. In the small interfering RNA (siRNA) knock-down study, 50 pmol of Mecp2 siRNA inhibited the MeCP2 expression in male- but not in female-derived NPCs with concomitant induction of postsynaptic proteins such as PSD95. Taken together, we suggest that the male-inclined reduction of MeCP2 expression is involved in the abnormal development of glutamatergic synapse and male preponderance in the VPA animal models of ASD.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kim KC, Choi CS, Kim JW, Han SH, Cheong JH, Ryu JH, Shin CY</name></author><summary type="html">Males are predominantly affected by autism spectrum disorders (ASD) with a prevalence ratio of 5:1. However, the underlying pathological mechanisms governing the male preponderance of ASD remain unclear. Recent studies suggested that epigenetic aberrations may cause synaptic dysfunctions, which might be related to the pathophysiology of ASD. In this study, we used rat offspring prenatally exposed to valproic acid (VPA) as an animal model of ASD. We found male-selective abnormalities in the kinetic profile of the excitatory glutamatergic synaptic protein expressions linked to N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor (NMDAR), alpha-amino-3-hydroxy-5-methyl-4-isoxazolepropionic acid receptor (AMPAR) and metabotropic glutamate receptor 5 (mGluR5) pathways in the prefrontal cortex of the VPA-exposed offspring at postnatal weeks 1, 2, and 4. Furthermore, VPA exposure showed a male-specific attenuation of the methyl-CpG-binding protein 2 (MeCP2) expressions both in the prefrontal cortex of offspring and in the gender-isolated neural progenitor cells (NPCs). In the gender-isolated NPCs culture, higher concentration of VPA induced an increased glutamatergic synaptic development along with decreased MeCP2 expression in both genders suggesting the role of MeCP2 in the modulation of synaptic development. In the small interfering RNA (siRNA) knock-down study, 50 pmol of Mecp2 siRNA inhibited the MeCP2 expression in male- but not in female-derived NPCs with concomitant induction of postsynaptic proteins such as PSD95. Taken together, we suggest that the male-inclined reduction of MeCP2 expression is involved in the abnormal development of glutamatergic synapse and male preponderance in the VPA animal models of ASD.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">High sucrose consumption during pregnancy induced ADHD-like behavioral phenotypes in mice offspring.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2015/12/10/highsucrose.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High sucrose consumption during pregnancy induced ADHD-like behavioral phenotypes in mice offspring." /><published>2015-12-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2015-12-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2015/12/10/highsucrose</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2015/12/10/highsucrose.html">&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the average consumption of sugar in humans from all ages has remarkably increased,
exceeding the recommended limit. Pregnancy is a critical time for the global development of offsprings who are vulnerable to the deleterious effects of environmental factors. In this study, we investigated whether high sucrose consumption during pregnancy could affect the attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)-like neurobehavioral outcomes in offspring mice. Pregnant mice were randomly grouped and orally administered with either water as control (Con) or 30% wt/vol sucrose diluted in water at 6 (Suc6) or 9 (Suc9) g/kg dosage per day from gestational days 6 to 15. After the weaning period, offspring mice underwent a series of behavioral testing for locomotor activity, attention, and impulsivity. Although there is no obvious difference in gross development of offspring mice such as weight gain, high sucrose-exposed offspring mice showed a significantly increased locomotor activity. Moreover, these mice exhibited a dose-dependent decrease in attention and increase in impulsivity. In the striatum, a significantly increased dopamine transporter (DAT) mRNA expression was found in the Suc9 group along with dose-dependent decreases in the Drd1, Drd2 and Drd4 dopamine receptor subtypes. Furthermore, synaptosomal DAT protein expression was increased about twofold in the Suc9 group. Prenatal fructose exposure also induced hyperactive behavior in offspring mice suggesting the essential role of fructose in the dysregulated neurobehavioral development. These findings suggest prenatal sucrose consumption as a new risk factor for ADHD, which may need further attention and investigation in humans.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Choi CS, Kim P, Park JH, Gonzales EL, Kim KC, Cho KS, Ko MJ, Yang SM, Seung H, Han SH, Ryu JH, Cheong JH, Shin CY.</name></author><summary type="html">In recent years, the average consumption of sugar in humans from all ages has remarkably increased, exceeding the recommended limit. Pregnancy is a critical time for the global development of offsprings who are vulnerable to the deleterious effects of environmental factors. In this study, we investigated whether high sucrose consumption during pregnancy could affect the attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)-like neurobehavioral outcomes in offspring mice. Pregnant mice were randomly grouped and orally administered with either water as control (Con) or 30% wt/vol sucrose diluted in water at 6 (Suc6) or 9 (Suc9) g/kg dosage per day from gestational days 6 to 15. After the weaning period, offspring mice underwent a series of behavioral testing for locomotor activity, attention, and impulsivity. Although there is no obvious difference in gross development of offspring mice such as weight gain, high sucrose-exposed offspring mice showed a significantly increased locomotor activity. Moreover, these mice exhibited a dose-dependent decrease in attention and increase in impulsivity. In the striatum, a significantly increased dopamine transporter (DAT) mRNA expression was found in the Suc9 group along with dose-dependent decreases in the Drd1, Drd2 and Drd4 dopamine receptor subtypes. Furthermore, synaptosomal DAT protein expression was increased about twofold in the Suc9 group. Prenatal fructose exposure also induced hyperactive behavior in offspring mice suggesting the essential role of fructose in the dysregulated neurobehavioral development. These findings suggest prenatal sucrose consumption as a new risk factor for ADHD, which may need further attention and investigation in humans.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Effects of atomoxetine on hyper-locomotive activity of the prenatally valproate-exposed rat offspring.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2014/09/10/Effects-of-atomoxetine.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Effects of atomoxetine on hyper-locomotive activity of the prenatally valproate-exposed rat offspring." /><published>2014-09-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2014-09-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2014/09/10/Effects%20of%20atomoxetine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2014/09/10/Effects-of-atomoxetine.html">&lt;p&gt;A substantial proportion of patients with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) display hyperactivity as a comorbid symptom. Exposure to valproic acid (VPA) during pregnancy produces ASD-like core behavioral phenotypes as well as hyperactivity in offspring both in human and experimental animals, which makes it a plausible model to study ASD-related neurobiological processes. In this study, we examined the effects of two of currently available attention defecit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) medications, methylphenidate (MPH) and atomoxetine (ATX) targeting dopamine and norepinephrine transporters (DAT and NET), respectively, on hyperactive behavior of prenatally VPA-exposed rat offspring. In the prefrontal cortex of VPA exposed rat offspring, both mRNA and protein expression of DAT was increased as compared with control. VPA function as a histone deacetylase inhibitor (HDACi) and chromatin immunoprecipitation experiments demonstrated that the acetylation of histone bound to DAT gene promoter was increased in VPA-exposed rat offspring suggesting epigenetic mechanism of DAT regulation. Similarly, the expression of NET was increased, possibly via increased histone acetylation in prefrontal cortex of VPA-exposed rat offspring. When we treated the VPA-exposed rat offspring with ATX, a NET selective inhibitor, hyperactivity was reversed to control level. In contrast, MPH that inhibits both DAT and NET, did not produce inhibitory effects against hyperactivity. The results suggest that NET abnormalities may underlie the hyperactive phenotype in VPA animal model of ASD. Profiling the pharmacological responsiveness as well as investigating underlying mechanism in multiple models of ASD and ADHD may provide more insights into the neurobiological correlates regulating the behavioral abnormalities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Choi CS, Hong M, Kim KC, Kim JW, Yang SM, Seung H, Ko MJ, Choi DH, You JS, Shin CY, Bahn GH</name></author><summary type="html">A substantial proportion of patients with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) display hyperactivity as a comorbid symptom. Exposure to valproic acid (VPA) during pregnancy produces ASD-like core behavioral phenotypes as well as hyperactivity in offspring both in human and experimental animals, which makes it a plausible model to study ASD-related neurobiological processes. In this study, we examined the effects of two of currently available attention defecit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) medications, methylphenidate (MPH) and atomoxetine (ATX) targeting dopamine and norepinephrine transporters (DAT and NET), respectively, on hyperactive behavior of prenatally VPA-exposed rat offspring. In the prefrontal cortex of VPA exposed rat offspring, both mRNA and protein expression of DAT was increased as compared with control. VPA function as a histone deacetylase inhibitor (HDACi) and chromatin immunoprecipitation experiments demonstrated that the acetylation of histone bound to DAT gene promoter was increased in VPA-exposed rat offspring suggesting epigenetic mechanism of DAT regulation. Similarly, the expression of NET was increased, possibly via increased histone acetylation in prefrontal cortex of VPA-exposed rat offspring. When we treated the VPA-exposed rat offspring with ATX, a NET selective inhibitor, hyperactivity was reversed to control level. In contrast, MPH that inhibits both DAT and NET, did not produce inhibitory effects against hyperactivity. The results suggest that NET abnormalities may underlie the hyperactive phenotype in VPA animal model of ASD. Profiling the pharmacological responsiveness as well as investigating underlying mechanism in multiple models of ASD and ADHD may provide more insights into the neurobiological correlates regulating the behavioral abnormalities.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Subchronic treatment of donepezil rescues impaired social, hyperactive, and stereotypic behavior in valproic acid-induced animal model of autism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2014/08/18/Subchronic-treatment-of-donepezil.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Subchronic treatment of donepezil rescues impaired social, hyperactive, and stereotypic behavior in valproic acid-induced animal model of autism" /><published>2014-08-18T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2014-08-18T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2014/08/18/Subchronic%20treatment%20of%20donepezil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2014/08/18/Subchronic-treatment-of-donepezil.html">&lt;p&gt;Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is a group of pervasive developmental disorders with core symptoms such as sociability deficit, language impairment, and repetitive/restricted behaviors. Although worldwide prevalence of ASD has been increased continuously, therapeutic agents to ameliorate the core symptoms especially social deficits, are very limited. In this study, we investigated therapeutic potential of donepezil for ASD using valproic acid-induced autistic animal model (VPA animal model). We found that prenatal exposure of valproic acid (VPA) induced dysregulation of cholinergic neuronal development, most notably the up-regulation of acetylcholinesterase (AChE) in the prefrontal cortex of affected rat and mouse offspring. Similarly, differentiating cortical neural progenitor cell in culture treated with VPA showed increased expression of AChE in vitro. Chromatin precipitation experiments revealed that acetylation of histone H3 bound to AChE promoter region was increased by VPA. In addition, other histone deacetyalse inhibitors (HDACIs) such as trichostatin A and sodium butyrate also increased the expression of AChE in differentiating neural progenitor cells suggesting the essential role of HDACIs in the regulation of AChE expression. For behavioral analysis, we injected PBS or donepezil (0.3 mg/kg) intraperitoneally to control and VPA mice once daily from postnatal day 14 all throughout the experiment. Subchronic treatment of donepezil improved sociability and prevented repetitive behavior and hyperactivity of VPA-treated mice offspring. Taken together, these results provide evidence that dysregulation of ACh system represented by the up-regulation of AChE may serve as an effective pharmacological therapeutic target against autistic behaviors in VPA animal model of ASD, which should be subjected for further investigation to verify the clinical relevance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kim JW, Seung H, Kwon KJ, Ko MJ, Lee EJ, Oh HA, Choi CS, Kim KC, Gonzales EL, You JS, Choi DH, Lee J, Han SH, Yang SM, Cheong JH, Shin CY, Bahn GH</name></author><summary type="html">Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is a group of pervasive developmental disorders with core symptoms such as sociability deficit, language impairment, and repetitive/restricted behaviors. Although worldwide prevalence of ASD has been increased continuously, therapeutic agents to ameliorate the core symptoms especially social deficits, are very limited. In this study, we investigated therapeutic potential of donepezil for ASD using valproic acid-induced autistic animal model (VPA animal model). We found that prenatal exposure of valproic acid (VPA) induced dysregulation of cholinergic neuronal development, most notably the up-regulation of acetylcholinesterase (AChE) in the prefrontal cortex of affected rat and mouse offspring. Similarly, differentiating cortical neural progenitor cell in culture treated with VPA showed increased expression of AChE in vitro. Chromatin precipitation experiments revealed that acetylation of histone H3 bound to AChE promoter region was increased by VPA. In addition, other histone deacetyalse inhibitors (HDACIs) such as trichostatin A and sodium butyrate also increased the expression of AChE in differentiating neural progenitor cells suggesting the essential role of HDACIs in the regulation of AChE expression. For behavioral analysis, we injected PBS or donepezil (0.3 mg/kg) intraperitoneally to control and VPA mice once daily from postnatal day 14 all throughout the experiment. Subchronic treatment of donepezil improved sociability and prevented repetitive behavior and hyperactivity of VPA-treated mice offspring. Taken together, these results provide evidence that dysregulation of ACh system represented by the up-regulation of AChE may serve as an effective pharmacological therapeutic target against autistic behaviors in VPA animal model of ASD, which should be subjected for further investigation to verify the clinical relevance.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chronic exposure to ethanol of male mice before mating produces attention deficit hyperactivity disorder-like phenotype along with epigenetic dysregulation of dopamine transporter expression in mouse offspring.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2014/05/10/chronic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chronic exposure to ethanol of male mice before mating produces attention deficit hyperactivity disorder-like phenotype along with epigenetic dysregulation of dopamine transporter expression in mouse offspring." /><published>2014-05-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2014-05-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2014/05/10/chronic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2014/05/10/chronic.html">&lt;p&gt;Preconception exposure to EtOH through the paternal route may affect neurobehavioral and developmental features of offspring. This study investigates the effects of paternal exposure to EtOH before conception on the hyperactivity, inattention, and impulsivity behavior of male offspring in mice. Sire mice were treated with EtOH in a concentration range approximating human binge drinking (0-4 g/kg/day EtOH) for 7 weeks and mated with untreated females mice to produce offspring. EtOH exposure to sire mice induced attention deficit hyperactivitydisorder (ADHD)-like hyperactive, inattentive, and impulsive behaviors in offspring. As a mechanistic link, both protein and mRNA expression of dopamine transporter (DAT), a key determinant of ADHD-like phenotypes in experimental animals and humans, were significantly decreased by paternal EtOH exposure in cerebral cortex and striatum of offspring mice along with increased methylation of a CpG region of the DAT gene promoter. The increase in methylation of DAT gene promoter was also observed in the sperm of sire mice, suggesting germline changes in the epigenetic methylation signature of DAT gene by EtOH exposure. In addition, the expression of two key regulators of methylation-dependent epigenetic regulation of functional gene expression, namely, MeCP2 and DNMT1, was markedly decreased in offspring cortex and striatum sired by EtOH-exposed mice. These results suggest that preconceptional exposure to EtOH through the paternal route induces behavioral changes in offspring, possibly via epigenetic changes in gene expression, which is essential for the regulation of ADHD-like behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kim P, Choi CS, Park JH, Joo SH, Kim SY, Ko HM, Kim KC, Jeon SJ, Park SH, Han SH, Ryu JH, Cheong JH, Han JY, Ko KN, Shin CY</name></author><summary type="html">Preconception exposure to EtOH through the paternal route may affect neurobehavioral and developmental features of offspring. This study investigates the effects of paternal exposure to EtOH before conception on the hyperactivity, inattention, and impulsivity behavior of male offspring in mice. Sire mice were treated with EtOH in a concentration range approximating human binge drinking (0-4 g/kg/day EtOH) for 7 weeks and mated with untreated females mice to produce offspring. EtOH exposure to sire mice induced attention deficit hyperactivitydisorder (ADHD)-like hyperactive, inattentive, and impulsive behaviors in offspring. As a mechanistic link, both protein and mRNA expression of dopamine transporter (DAT), a key determinant of ADHD-like phenotypes in experimental animals and humans, were significantly decreased by paternal EtOH exposure in cerebral cortex and striatum of offspring mice along with increased methylation of a CpG region of the DAT gene promoter. The increase in methylation of DAT gene promoter was also observed in the sperm of sire mice, suggesting germline changes in the epigenetic methylation signature of DAT gene by EtOH exposure. In addition, the expression of two key regulators of methylation-dependent epigenetic regulation of functional gene expression, namely, MeCP2 and DNMT1, was markedly decreased in offspring cortex and striatum sired by EtOH-exposed mice. These results suggest that preconceptional exposure to EtOH through the paternal route induces behavioral changes in offspring, possibly via epigenetic changes in gene expression, which is essential for the regulation of ADHD-like behaviors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prefrontal cortical and striatal transcriptional responses to the reinforcing effect of repeated methylphenidate treatment in the spontaneously hypertensive rat, animal model of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD).</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2014/05/06/Prefrontal-cortical-and-striatal-transcriptional.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prefrontal cortical and striatal transcriptional responses to the reinforcing effect of repeated methylphenidate treatment in the spontaneously hypertensive rat, animal model of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)." /><published>2014-05-06T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2014-05-06T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2014/05/06/Prefrontal%20cortical%20and%20striatal%20transcriptional</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/trineurotec/2014/05/06/Prefrontal-cortical-and-striatal-transcriptional.html">&lt;p&gt;BACKGROUND:
Methylphenidate is the most commonly used stimulant drug for the treatment of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder(ADHD). Research has found that methylphenidate is a “reinforcer” and that individuals with ADHD also abuse this medication. Nevertheless, the molecular consequences of long-term recreational methylphenidate use or abuse in individuals with ADHD are not yet fully known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;METHODS:
Spontaneously hypertensive rats (SHR), the most validated and widely used ADHD animal model, were pretreated with methylphenidate (5 mg/kg, i.p.) during their adolescence (post-natal day [PND] 42-48) and tested for subsequent methylphenidate-induced conditioned place preference (CPP) and self-administration. Thereafter, the differentially expressed genes in the prefrontal cortex (PFC) and striatum of representative methylphenidate-treated SHRs, which showed CPP to and self-administration of methylphenidate, were analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RESULTS:
Genome-wide transcriptome profiling analyses revealed 30 differentially expressed genes in the PFC, which include transcripts involved in apoptosis (e.g. S100a9, Angptl4, Nfkbia), transcription (Cebpb, Per3), and neuronal plasticity (Homer1, Jam2, Asap1). In contrast, 306 genes were differentially expressed in the striatum and among them, 252 were downregulated. The main functional categories overrepresented among the downregulated genes include those involved in cell adhesion (e.g. Pcdh10, Ctbbd1, Itgb6), positive regulation of apoptosis (Perp, Taf1, Api5), (Notch3, Nsbp1, Sik1), mitochondrion organization (Prps18c, Letm1, Uqcrc2), and ubiquitin-mediated proteolysis (Nedd4, Usp27x, Ube2d2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CONCLUSION:
Together, these changes indicate methylphenidate-induced neurotoxicity, altered synaptic and neuronal plasticity, energy metabolism and ubiquitin-dependent protein degradation in the brains of methylphenidate-treated SHRs, which showed methylphenidate CPP and self-administration. In addition, these findings may also reflect cognitive impairment associated with chronic methylphenidate use as demonstrated in preclinical studies. Future studies are warranted to determine the clinical significance of the present findings with regard to long-term recreational methylphenidate use or abuse in individuals with ADHD.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dela Peña I, Kim HJ, Sohn A, Kim BN, Han DH, Ryu JH, Shin CY, Noh M, Cheong JH</name></author><summary type="html">BACKGROUND: Methylphenidate is the most commonly used stimulant drug for the treatment of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder(ADHD). Research has found that methylphenidate is a “reinforcer” and that individuals with ADHD also abuse this medication. Nevertheless, the molecular consequences of long-term recreational methylphenidate use or abuse in individuals with ADHD are not yet fully known.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Advanced pharmacotherapy evidenced by pathogenesis of autism spectrum disorder</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2014/04/10/Advanced-pharmacotherapy-evidenced-by-pathogenesis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advanced pharmacotherapy evidenced by pathogenesis of autism spectrum disorder" /><published>2014-04-10T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2014-04-10T00:00:00+09:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2014/04/10/Advanced%20pharmacotherapy%20evidenced%20by%20pathogenesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/neuroventi/2014/04/10/Advanced-pharmacotherapy-evidenced-by-pathogenesis.html">&lt;p&gt;In clinical practice, pharmacological treatment is mostly focused on behavioral symptoms in everyday life. Nevertheless, persistent effort continues to develop medication for causal treatment. Recent changes in diagnostic criteria from Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 4th edition, text revision (DSM-IV-TR) to DSM-5 would affect not only diagnosing approaches, but also therapeutic approaches. Because previous pervasive developmental disorders have been integrated into a single entity, the autism spectrum disorder (ASD), we have to prepare for what medications are valuable for the ASD. In this article, we reviewed the following etiological treatment: acetylcholine and glutamate related medicine; amino acid medicine such as secretin, endogenous opioid, and oxytocin; complementary and alternative medicine such as chelating agents, vitamins, and omega-3; promising drugs related to the scope of pharmacogenetics currently under study.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lee YJ, Oh SH, Park C, Hong M, Lee AR, Yoo HJ, Shin CY, Cheon KA, Bahn GH</name></author><summary type="html">In clinical practice, pharmacological treatment is mostly focused on behavioral symptoms in everyday life. Nevertheless, persistent effort continues to develop medication for causal treatment. Recent changes in diagnostic criteria from Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 4th edition, text revision (DSM-IV-TR) to DSM-5 would affect not only diagnosing approaches, but also therapeutic approaches. Because previous pervasive developmental disorders have been integrated into a single entity, the autism spectrum disorder (ASD), we have to prepare for what medications are valuable for the ASD. In this article, we reviewed the following etiological treatment: acetylcholine and glutamate related medicine; amino acid medicine such as secretin, endogenous opioid, and oxytocin; complementary and alternative medicine such as chelating agents, vitamins, and omega-3; promising drugs related to the scope of pharmacogenetics currently under study.</summary></entry></feed>